Guide to the Frederick Stoever Dickson Collection Regarding Henry Fielding
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
- Frederick Stoever Dickson Papers, 1733-1931; Series I; 10.11; (21 boxes)
  - WRITINGS
    - Writings of Others Related to Fielding
      - Hughes, Helen Sard
        - "Fielding's Indebtedness to James Ralph," article, offprint from Modern Philology, 1922 Aug (Box 6, Folder 164)
        - "Notes on Eighteenth-Century Fictional Translations," article, offprint from Modern Philology, 1919 Aug (Box 6, Folder 165)
      - Jensen, Gerard Edward
        - "An Apology for the Life of Mrs. Shamela Andrews, 1741," open letter, printed version, Modern Language Notes, 1916 May (Box 6, Folder 166)
        - "The Convent-Garden Journal Extraordinary," open letter, printed version, Modern Language Notes, 1919 Jan (Box 6, Folder 167)
        - "The Crisis: A Sermon," open letter, printed version, Modern Language Notes, signed, 1916 Nov (Box 6, Folder 168)
        - "Fashionable Society in Fielding's Time," article, offprint, Publications of the Modern Language Association of America, 1916 (Box 6, Folder 169)
      - Keightley, Thomas
        - "On the Life and Writings of Henry Fielding," article, printed version, Fraser's Magazine, 1858 (Box 6, Folder 170)
        - "Tom Jones," article, draft, holograph, signed, n.d. (Box 6, Folder 171)
      - Lathrop, G. P.
        - "Growth of the Novel," article, printed version, The Atlantic Monthly, 1874 Jun (Box 6, Folder 172)
      - Lewin, Walter
        - "The Abuse of Fiction," article, printed version, The Forum, 1889 Aug (Box 6, Folder 173)
      - Lindner, Felix
        - Henry Fielding's dramatische Werke, English translation, incomplete, typescript and holograph, corrected (Box 6, Folder 174)
          Includes letter from W. E. Schultz to Dickson
      - Lobban, J. H.
        - "Henry Fielding," article, printed version, Blackwood's Edinburgh Magazine, 1907 Apr (Box 6, Folder 175)
      - Lounsbury, Thomas Raynesford
        - "Fielding," article, printed version, Century Magazine, n.d. (Box 6, Folder 176)
      - Lowell, James Russell
        - "Inscription for a Memorial Bust of Fielding," inscription, printed version, The Critic, 1890 Aug 30 (Box 6, Folder 177)
      - Luders, Charles Henry
        - "When Fielding Wrote," poem, printed version, The Critic, 1888 Apr 14 (Box 6, Folder 178)
      - Minchin, Harry Christopher
        - "Henry Fielding and his Writings," article, printed version, The Fortnightly Review, 1907 Apr (Box 6, Folder 179)
      - Moore, George
        - "Avowals," article, printed version, Lippincott's Magazine, 1903 Sep (Box 6, Folder 180)
      - Nichols, Charles W.
        - "Fielding Notes," article, printed version, Modern Language Notes, 1919 Apr (Box 6, Folder 181)
        - "Fielding's 'Tumble-Down Dick'," article, printed version, Modern Language Notes, 1923 Nov (Box 6, Folder 182)
      - Norris, Hugh
        - "Fielding and Sarah Andrew," note, printed version, The Athenaeum, 1883 Jun 16 (Box 6, Folder 183)
      - Phelps, William Lyon
        - "The Advance of the English Novel," article, printed version, The Bookman, 1915 Dec (Box 6, Folder 184)
      - Pollard, Alfred W. (Alfred William)
        - "Notes on Old Books," review, printed version, The Library, 1917 Jan (Box 6, Folder 185)
          See also: De Castro, John Paul Box 5, folder 144
      - Prideaux, W. F.
        - "Fielding's "Tom Jones"," open letter, printed version, Notes and Queries, 1884 Mar 29 (Box 6, Folder 186)
      - Purcell, E.
        - "English Men of Letters," review of Austin Dobson's Fielding, printed version, The Academy, 1883 May 5 (Box 6, Folder 187)
      - Saintsbury, George
        - "Henry Fielding," article, printed version, The Bookman, 1907 Apr (Box 6, Folder 188)
      - Scott, Walter, Sir
        - "Prefatory Memoir to Fielding," article, printed version, Museum of Foreign Literature and Science, 1824 Aug (Box 6, Folder 189)
      - Smith, George Barnett
        - "Our First Great Novelist," article, printed version, Macmillan's Magazine, 1874 May (Box 7, Folder 190)
      - Stapfer, Paul
        - "La grand classique du roman anglais," article, printed version, Revue des deux mondes, 1890 Sep 15 (Box 7, Folder 191)
      - Stevenson, Robert Louis
        - "Some Gentleman in Fiction," article, printed version, Scribner's Magazine, 1888 Jun (Box 7, Folder 192)
      - Thackeray, William Makepeace
        - "A Collection of Unpublished Letters of Thackeray," letters, printed version, Scribner's Magazine, n.d. (Box 7, Folder 193)
      - Wells, John Edwin
        - "The "Champion" and Some Unclaimed Essays by Henry Fielding," article, offprint from Englische Studien (Box 7, Folder 194)
        - "The Dating of Shenstone's Letters," offprint from Anglia, inscribed, 1912 (Box 7, Folder 195)
        - "Fielding's 'Champion' and Captain Hercules Vinegar," article, offprint from The Modern Language Review, 1913 Apr (Box 7, Folder 196)
        - "Fielding's Champion --More Notes," article, printed version, Modern Language Notes, inscribed, 1920 Jan (Box 7, Folder 197)
        - "Fielding's Choice of Signature for The Champion offprint from The Modern Language Review, 1912 Jul (Box 7, Folder 198)
        - "Fielding's First Poem to Walpole and his Garret in 1730," open letter, printed version, Modern Language Notes, signed, 1914 Jan (Box 7, Folder 199)
        - "Fielding's Signatures in 'The Champion'..." open letter, offprint from The Modern Language Review, 1912 Jan (Box 7, Folder 200)
        - "Henry Fielding and The Crisis ," open letter, offprint from Modern Language Notes, 1912 Jun (Box 7, Folder 201)
        - "Henry Fielding and the History of Charles XII," article, offprint, JEGP. Journal of English and Germanic Philology, 1912 Oct (Box 7, Folder 202)
        - "News for Bibliophiles," article, printed version, The Nation, 1912 Apr 25 (Box 7, Folder 203)
        - "Some New Facts Concerning Fielding's Tumble-down Dick and Pasquin ," article, offprint, Modern Language Notes, 1913 May (Box 7, Folder 204)
      - Wilson, Posey S.
        - "The Boxing Gloves Suggestion," letter to the editor, printed version, The Sun, 1904 Feb 24 (Box 7, Folder 205)
      - Young, Stark
        - "Fielding," review of The History of Henry Fielding, printed version, The New Republic, 1919 Apr 12 (Box 7, Folder 206)
      - Unidentified
        - "Dobson's Fielding ," review, printed version, The Atlantic Monthly, 1883 Jul (Box 7, Folder 207)
        - "Editor's Easy Chair," open letter, printed version, Harper's New Monthly Magazine, 1875 Apr (Box 7, Folder 208)
        - "Editor's Easy Chair," open letter, printed version, Harper's New Monthly Magazine, 1860 Feb (Box 7, Folder 209)
        - "English Classics and Critics," review, printed version, The Athenaeum, 1904 May 7 (Box 7, Folder 210)
        - "The English "Hall of Fame"," article, printed version, The Literary Digest, n.d. (Box 7, Folder 211)
        - "Facetious Writer," open letter, printed version, Notes and Queries, 1856 Apr 19 (Box 7, Folder 212)
        - Fielding, review, printed version, The Athenaeum, 1883 Apr 28 (Box 7, Folder 213)
        - "Fielding and Thackeray," review, printed version, The North British Review, 1855 Nov (Box 7, Folder 214)
        - "Fielding's Miser ," article, offprint, Huntington Library Bulletin, 1931 May (Box 7, Folder 215)
          Includes card inscribed by Stanley E. Read
        - "Fielding's Newspapers," article, printed version, Chamber's Journal, 1860 Sep 1 (Box 7, Folder 216)
        - "Fielding's Novels," article, printed version, Littell's Living Age, 1877 Apr 7 (Box 7, Folder 217)
        - "Henry Fielding," review of The History on Henry Fielding, printed version, The Times Literary Supplement, 1919 Aug 14
        - "Henry Fielding's Family," biography, printed version, The Athenaeum, 1905 Nov 25 (Box 7, Folder 218)
        - Histoire de Tom Jones, ou l'enfant trouvé, review, printed version, The Gentleman's Magazine, 1750 Apr (Box 7, Folder 219)
        - "Historical Sketches of the Reign of George II," article, printed version, Blackwood's Edinburgh Magazine, 1869 Mar (Box 7, Folder 220)
        - The History of Henry Fielding, review, printed version, The Atlantic Monthly, 1919 (Box 7, Folder 221)
        - "Hours in a Library: Fielding's Novels," article, printed version, The Cornhill Magazine, 1877 Feb (Box 7, Folder 222)
        - "How Fielding Measures up with Modern Novelists," article, printed version, The Literary Digest, 1907 (Box 7, Folder 223)
        - ""Immoral" Fiction in Britain and America," article, printed version, The Literary Digest, 1907 (Box 7, Folder 224)
        - "Judicial Puzzles--Elizabeth Canning," article, printed version, Blackwood's Edinburgh Magazine, 1860 May (Box 7, Folder 225)
        - "Lawrence's Life of Fielding," review, printed version, Bentley's Miscellany, n.d. (Box 7, Folder 226)
        - The life of Henry Fielding, review, printed version, The Quarterly Review, n.d. (Box 7, Folder 227)
        - "The Noblest Novelist of Them All," review of The History of Henry Fielding, printed version, The Nation, 1919 Feb 22 (Box 7, Folder 228)
        - [On Periodical Papers], review of Nathan Drake's Essays, printed version, The Quarterly Review (Box 7, Folder 229)
        - "Unveiling of the Bust of at the Shire Hall, Taunton," review, printed version, The Graphic, 1883 Sep 8 (Box 7, Folder 230)
        - "A Word about Tom Jones," article, printed version, Blackwood's Edinburgh Magazine, 1860 Mar (Box 7, Folder 231)
    - Writings of Others Not Related to Fielding
      - Unidentified
        - "The Education of the Blind," review, printed version, The North American Review, 1933 Jul (Box 7, Folder 234)
        - [Harliquinade], holograph, signed, 1754 (Box 7, Folder 233)
  - SUBJECT FILES
    Bibliographic material
    - Books, n.d. (Box 8, Folder 234)
    - Books, n.d. (Box 9, Folder 235)
    - "Miscellanies", n.d. (Box 9, Folder 236)
    - "Miscellanies", n.d. (Box 10, Folder 237)
    - "Miscellanies", n.d. (Box 11, Folder 238)
    - "Miscellanies", n.d. (Box 12, Folder 239)
    - Art, n.d. (Box 12, Folder 240)
    - Works of Others, n.d. (Box 12, Folder 241)
    - Works of Others, n.d. (Box 13, Folder 242)
    - Works of Others, n.d. (Box 14, Folder 243)
    - Works of Others, n.d. (Box 15, Folder 244)
    - Works of Others, n.d. (Box 16, Folder 245)
    - Works of Others, n.d. (Box 17, Folder 246)
    - Periodicals, n.d. (Box 18, Folder 247)
    - Periodicals, n.d. (Box 19, Folder 248)
    - "Catalogue of the Law Library of Henry Fielding", n.d. (Box 19, Folder 249)
    - "Catalogue of the Miscellaneous Library of Henry Fielding", n.d. (Box 19, Folder 250)
    - Card Catalog, n.d. (Box 20, Folder 251)
    - Clippings
      - The Athenaeum, 1851, 1879 (Box 21, Folder 252)
      - The Cornhill Magazine, 1861-63, n.d. (Box 21, Folder 253)
      - The Critic, 1890-1901, n.d. (Box 21, Folder 254)
      - The Gentleman's Magazine, 1733-1801, n.d. (Box 21, Folder 255)
      - Literature, 1899 (Box 21, Folder 256)
      - Macmillan's Magazine, n.d. (Box 21, Folder 257)
      - "Miscellaneous", 1757-1920, n.d. (Box 21, Folder 258)
      - New York Times, 1901-20, n.d. (Box 21, Folder 259)
      - Notes and Queries, 1855-1917 (Box 21, Folder 260)
      - Publications of the Modern Language Association of America, 1916 Mar (Box 21, Folder 261)
      - The Sun, 1903-15 (Box 21, Folder 262)
    - "Fieldingiana", n.d. (Box 21, Folder 263)
    - "Maps Illustrating Tom Jones", 1747-65, n.d. (Box 21, Folder 264)
- Material from Other Sources, 1913-37; Series II; 0.21; (1 box)
  Series II, Material from Other Sources, is organized into two subseries: Correspondence and Writings.
  - CORRESPONDENCE
    - Dickson, Frederick Stoever, 1913-22 (Box 22, Folder 265-268)
    - Nodder, Reverand Henry M., 1920-21 (Box 22, Folder 269)
    - Owen, Daniel E. (Daniel Edward), 1920 Nov (Box 22, Folder 270)
    - Taft, Arthur Irving, 1920 Nov 12 (Box 22, Folder 271)
    - Turner, Timothy G. (Timothy Gilman), 1921 (Box 22, Folder 272)
      Includes poem
  - WRITINGS
    - Balderstone, Katharine, C.
      - "Goldsmith's Supposed Attack on Fielding," note, printed version, Modern Language Notes, 1927 Mar (Box 22, Folder 273)
    - Crane, Ronald S. (Ronald Salmon)
      - "English Literature, 1660-1800," bibliography, offprint from Philological Quarterly, 1931 Apr (Box 22, Folder 274)
    - Jensen, Gerard E.
      - "Proposals for a Definitive Edition of Fielding's Tom Jones ," article, offprint from The Library, 1937 (Box 22, Folder 275)
    - McCutcheon, Roger P[hilip?]
      - "Amelia, or the Distressed Wife," note, printed version, Modern Language Notes, 1927 Jan (Box 22, Folder 276)
    - McKillop, Alan Dugald
      - "The Personal Relations Between Fielding and Richardson," article, offprint from Modern Philology, 1931 May (Box 22, Folder 277)
    - Moore, C. A.
      - "Whig Panegyric Verse, 1700-1760," article, offprint from Publications of the Modern Language Association of America, 1926 Jun (Box 22, Folder 278)
    - Nichols, Charles Washburn
      - "Fielding and the Cibbers," article, offprint from Philological Quarterly, 1922 Oct (Box 22, Folder 279)
      - "Fielding's Satire on Pantomine," article, offprint from Publications of the Modern Language Association of America, 1931 Dec (Box 22, Folder 280)
      - "Social Satire in Fielding's Pasquin and The Historical Register ," article, offprint from Philological Quarterly, 1924 Oct (Box 22, Folder 281)
    - Seymour, Mabel
      - "Fielding's History of the Forty-five," article, offprint from Philological Quarterly, 1935 Apr (Box 22, Folder 282)
    - Taylor, Houghton Wells
      - "Fielding upon Cibber," article, offprint from Modern Philology, 1931 Aug (Box 22, Folder 283)
- Oversize, 1.67; (1 box)
  - The Times Literary Supplement review of The History of Henry Fielding (In Series I), 1919 Aug 14 (Box 23, Folder 284)
  - Maps (In Series I), 1747-66 (Box 23, Folder 285)
- Restricted Fragile, 0.21; (1 box)
  Conditions Governing Access
  Box 5: Restricted fragile material. Reference surrogates have been substituted in the main files. For further information consult the appropriate curator.
  - Box 2, folder 36 (Box 24, Folder 286)
  - Box 5, folder 114 (Box 24, Folder 287)
  - Box 5, folder 121 (Box 24, Folder 288)
  - Box 21, folder 258 (Box 24, Folder 289)
  - Box 21, folder 259 (Box 24, Folder 290)
  - Box 21, folder 260 (Box 24, Folder 291)
  - Box 21, folder 262 (Box 24, Folder 292)